<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Amedeo Palopoli</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Amedeo Palopoli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amedeopalopoli.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publications</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/blog/force-ssl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amedeopalopoli.com/blog/force-ssl/</guid><description>&lt;!--

This page represents the landing page for "publications" section. It is also shown under the homepage header for "publications". It should be therefore relatively short and sweet.

\-->
&lt;p>A collection of articles, presentations or talks, most likely on Culture and DevOps, because let&amp;rsquo;s admit it, they are one in the same ;)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>[TALK] Beyond cloud borders with Aruba Managed Kubernetes and Liqo</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/italy-cloudnativedays2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/italy-cloudnativedays2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a period marked by the rapid adoption of multi-cloud solutions and the constant pursuit of AI capabilities, the need for efficient and flexible resource management becomes crucial. Aruba Managed Kubernetes and Liqo offer new ways to address these challenges. Aruba Managed Kubernetes simplifies deployment and ensures security and high availability. The multi-cloud federation enabled by Liqo allows for effective and seamless resource management, as well as enabling workload mobility. Together, they enhance operational flexibility—for example, by optimizing the AI value chain and enabling GPU sharing—and more broadly by managing complex, adaptable cloud architectures. This integration not only increases efficiency but also opens new paths for innovation in the hybrid cloud space.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>[TALK] Kubernetes Like Lego: Building the New Standard for European Cloud APIs</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/italy-cloudnativedays2025/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/italy-cloudnativedays2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>In today’s technology landscape, Kubernetes has established itself as an essential tool for container orchestration, becoming a benchmark platform for cloud innovation. In this session, we will explore how a Kubernetes-based approach has been applied in the design and implementation of SECA’s advanced cloud APIs, strengthening the digital infrastructure for the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will present practical use cases that showcase the benefits of this architecture, highlighting the importance of the open-source community in the project’s evolution. Join us for this exploration of how Kubernetes is not just a technical implementation, but the foundation on which to build the next level of cloud innovation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Container orchestration engines: A thorough functional and performance comparison</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/containerorchestration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/containerorchestration/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the last decade, novel software architectural patterns, such as microservices, have emerged to improve application modularity and to streamline their development, testing, scaling, and component replacement. To support these new trends, new practices as DevOps methodologies and tools, promoting better cooperation between software development and operations teams, have emerged to support automation and monitoring throughout the whole software construction lifecycle. That affected positively several IT companies, but also helped the transition to the softwarization of complex telco infrastructures in the last years.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>QoS and performance metrics for container-based virtualization in cloud environments</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/performancemetrics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/performancemetrics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Current cloud deployments heavily depend on hypervisor-based virtualizations. The overarching characteristics of Docker and containerization have given them a momentum in their widespread adoption recently as alternatives for their counterparts. However, little research has been done for comparing the QoS of both technologies, thus leaving the domain without widely accepted performance metrics. Aiming at informing the decision of the best fit in a specific cloud deployment, we have designed performance metrics that compare the performance of both designs in an in-house cluster deployed by using OpenStack. We focus on well-established representatives as baselines, including KVM from the hypervisor-based side, LXD from the container-based side in addition to Docker.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Containerization in Cloud Computing: performance analysis of virtualization architectures</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/thesisbook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/thesisbook/</guid><description>&lt;p>The increasing adoption of cloud computing is strongly influenced by emerging of technologies whose aim is to improve the development and deployment processes of enterprise applications. The goal of this thesis is to investigate one of these solutions, called “containerization”, and deeply analyze how this solution can be included in cloud infrastructures as an alternative to complementary solutions like virtual machines. So far, the virtual machine model has been the predominant solution. The key differentiator nature that containers offer has stimulated an increasing adoption of this technology because improves resource management, resource sharing, and it guarantees substantial improvements regarding provisioning time of single instances.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amedeopalopoli.com/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p>Feel free to reach out through any of the following:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Search Results</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amedeopalopoli.com/search/</guid><description>&lt;p>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related &lt;code>search&lt;/code> layout template.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="initial-setup">Initial setup&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>[outputs]
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;]
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h2 id="searching-additional-fileds">Searching additional fileds&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>