<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CNCF on Amedeo Palopoli</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/tags/cncf/</link><description>Recent content in CNCF on Amedeo Palopoli</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amedeopalopoli.com/tags/cncf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>[TALK] Kubernetes Like Lego: Building the New Standard for European Cloud APIs</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/italy-cloudnativedays2025/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/italy-cloudnativedays2025/</guid><description>&lt;p>In today’s technology landscape, Kubernetes has established itself as an essential tool for container orchestration, becoming a benchmark platform for cloud innovation. In this session, we will explore how a Kubernetes-based approach has been applied in the design and implementation of SECA’s advanced cloud APIs, strengthening the digital infrastructure for the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will present practical use cases that showcase the benefits of this architecture, highlighting the importance of the open-source community in the project’s evolution. Join us for this exploration of how Kubernetes is not just a technical implementation, but the foundation on which to build the next level of cloud innovation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>[TALK] Beyond cloud borders with Aruba Managed Kubernetes and Liqo</title><link>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/italy-cloudnativedays2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://amedeopalopoli.com/publications/italy-cloudnativedays2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>In a period marked by the rapid adoption of multi-cloud solutions and the constant pursuit of AI capabilities, the need for efficient and flexible resource management becomes crucial. Aruba Managed Kubernetes and Liqo offer new ways to address these challenges. Aruba Managed Kubernetes simplifies deployment and ensures security and high availability. The multi-cloud federation enabled by Liqo allows for effective and seamless resource management, as well as enabling workload mobility. Together, they enhance operational flexibility—for example, by optimizing the AI value chain and enabling GPU sharing—and more broadly by managing complex, adaptable cloud architectures. This integration not only increases efficiency but also opens new paths for innovation in the hybrid cloud space.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>